The Thirteenth Tale is a tv movie, drama, mystery film directed by James Kent.
Biographer Margaret Lea travels to the isolated rural mansion of the famous
writer Vida Winter, who asks her to write her biography.
Although initially she is reluctant, as Vida is known for constantly distorting the facts of her life, Margaret soon becomes fascinated
with the story of a dark childhood, a disturbing tale that leads her to finally confront the traumas of her own past.
Vida Winter, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
Margaret, played by Olivia Colman.
John the Dig, played by Robert Pugh.
Hester Barrow, played by Alexandra Roach.
Dr. Clifton, played by Steven Mackintosh.
Dr. Mawsley, played by Tom Goodman-Hill.
The Thirteenth Tale is a British drama television film that
first broadcast on BBC Two on 30 December 2013.
It is an adaptation of Diane Setterfield's 2006
gothic novel The Thirteenth Tale.
The film explores themes of countryside, based on novel or book, family
secrets, isolated house, brother sister relationship.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.